《行尸走肉》
(勿在此地逗留  勿与犯人交谈)
好了  我们把那辆车也弄进来
Okay, let's get the other car in.
把它们停在院子西边的入口处
We'll park 'em in the west entry of the yard.
很好  车都堆外面
Good. Our vehicles camped out there
就像在邀请别人进来住宿
look like a giant "Vacancy" sign.
然后我们还得把尸体堆起来
After that, we need to load up these corpses
一起烧掉
so we can burn 'em.
够干一天了
Gonna be a long day.
格伦和玛姬在哪里  我们缺人手
Where's Glenn and Maggie? We could use some help.
在哨塔上
Up in the guard tower.
哨塔
Guard tower?
他们昨晚就上去了
They were just up there last night.
格伦  玛姬
Glenn! Maggie!
啥事呀  伙计们
Hey, what's up, guys?
-你来吗  -啥
- You coming? - What?
你来不来
You comin'?
快点  我们人手不够
Come on, we could use a hand.
好  我们马上下来
Yeah, we'll be right down.
一群变态
Sickos.
瑞克
Hey, Rick.
跟我来
Come with me.
不许再接近了
That's close enough.
-我们说好的  -拜托  先生  我们知道
- We had an agreement. - Please, mister. We know that.
我们是说好了  但你要理解...
We made a deal. But you gotta understand...
我们没法再住那了
we can't live in that place another minute.
你懂吗  那些尸体
You follow me? All the bodies--
都是我们认识的人
people we knew.
血和脑浆到处都是
Blood, brains everywhere.
-阴魂不散  -为什么不把尸体搬出去
- There's ghosts. - Why don't you move the bodies out?
-应该把它们全烧了  -我们试了
- You should be burning them. - We tried.
-真的  -监狱那头的栅栏坏了
- We did. - The fence is down on the far side of the prison.
每次我们把尸体搬出去  那些东西就守在那
Every time we drag a body out, those things just line up.
只能把尸体扔下  赶紧逃回里面
Dropping the body and just running back inside.
我们与托马斯和安德鲁毫无关系
Look, we had nothing to do with Thomas and Andrew.
真的
Nothing.
之前那事  对我们已是警示
You trying to prove a point? You proved it, bro.
只要能加入你们  我们愿做牛做马
We'll do whatever it takes to be part of your group.
求你了
Just please, please...
别让我们待在那种地方
don't make us live in that place.
这事没有商量余地
Our deal is not negotiable.
要么待在那个牢区  要么离开监狱
You either live in your cell block, or you leave.
我就知道这是浪费时间
I told you this was a waste of time.
他们和杀了我们同伴的人是一丘之貉
They ain't no different than the pricks who shot up our boys.
你知道这一周里
You know how many friends' corpses
我们搬了多少朋友的尸体吗
we had to drag out this week?
就这么把他们扔出去
Just threw 'em out, like.
他们是好人啊
Humph. These were good guys.
和我们一起
Good guys who had our backs
抵抗监狱里的恶霸
against the really bad dudes in the joint,
比如托马斯和安德鲁
like Thomas and Andrew.
我们都犯过错  才被关进监狱
We've all made mistakes to get in here, chief.
我可没打算装成圣人
And I'm not gonna pretend to be a saint,
但你要知道
but believe me...
我们都已经付出了代价
we've paid our due--
我们宁愿出去闯荡
enough that we would rather hit that road
也不会再回那个狗窝去
than to go back into that shithole.
不是吧  老兄
C'mon, dude.
你开玩笑的吧
Are you serious?
让他们住你隔壁
You want them living in a cell next to you?
他们会伺机抢走我们的武器
They'll just be waiting for a chance to grab our weapons.
你希望睡不踏实吗
You want to go back to sleeping with one eye open?
我从没睡踏实过
I never stopped.
让他们加入吧
Bring them into the fold.
让他们离开
If we send them off packing,
就几乎是宣告了他们的死刑
we might as well execute them ourselves.
我不知道  阿克塞尔情绪不太稳定
I don't know. Axel seems a little unstable.
我们经历了那么多磨难
After all we've been through?
好不容易才得到这个地方
We fought so hard for all this,
如果他们想窃取怎么办
what if they decide to take it?
一直以来都是我们一起并肩作战
It's just been us for so long.
他们是陌生人  我不...
They're strangers. I don't--
这些人突然在身边感觉有点怪
It feels weird all of a sudden to have these other people around.
可你当初也接受了我们
You brought us in.
是的  但是你们出现时抱着个受伤的男孩
Yeah, but you turned up with a shot boy in your arms.
我们别无选择
Didn't give us a choice.
他们连杀行尸都不会
They can't even kill walkers.
归根结底  他们是罪犯
They're convicts, bottom line.
他们两个或许还没
Those two might actually
我们手上的人命多
have less blood on their hands than we do.
我了解这种人
I get guys like this.
我和他们一起长大
Hell, I grew up with them.
他们很堕落  但不是精神病
They're degenerates, but they ain't psychos.
一念之差  说不定我也会进监狱
I could have been in there with them
而不是跟你们在一起
just as easy as I'm out here with you guys.
-所以你同意我  -当然不
- So are you with me? - Hell, no.
让他们像我们一样去外边
Let 'em take their chances out on the road
-碰碰运气  -我的意思是  达里尔
- just like we did. - What I'm saying, Daryl--
我刚当警察时  逮捕了个孩子
When I was a rookie, I arrested this kid.
19岁  因刺死女友而被通缉
Nineteen years old, wanted for stabbing his girlfriend.
孩子在审问和审判期间
The kid blubbered like a baby
哭得像个婴儿
during the interrogation, during the trial--
欺骗了陪审团
suckered the jury.
他以证据不足为由无罪释放
He was acquitted due to insufficient evidence
两周之后
and then, two weeks later,
又射杀了另外一个女孩
shot another girl.
我们经历了太多了
We've been through too much.
我们跟他们的约定不会变
Our deal with them stands.
挺不错吧
Pretty amazing.
要有更多弹药  我们可以解决一大群行尸
We find more ammo, we could cut down a whole pack of biters.
我听说你和安德莉亚今天要走
I hear you and Andrea are leaving today.
真可惜啊
That's a shame.
我们就缺你这样的强手
We could use a soldier like you.
我看你不缺人
You seem like you're holding your own.
连国民警卫队都被灭了
Even the National Guard was overrun.
就算受过军事训练  也应付不了行尸成群
No amount of training can prepare you for the world today.
士兵为什么不开车逃跑...
You'd think one soldier would drive away--
行尸行动可很缓慢
especially against something so slow.
那些人很英雄主义
Those men were heroes.
不会丢下自己人逃跑
Not the kind to leave anyone behind.
如果我们能早到点...
If only we'd gotten there sooner...
如果你能帮我们
and you were with us.
很多弹孔啊
Lots of bullet holes.
行尸什么时候会用武器了
You think biters figured out how to use weapons?
他们几星期前一定碰到土匪了
They must have encountered bandits weeks ago.
外面世界很丑陋的  但是...
It's ugly out there, but then...
你比任何人都清楚
you know that better than anyone.
韦尔斯身上发生的事太不幸了
Too bad what happened to Welles.
确实
It is.
斯蒂文斯医生没能救活他
Dr. Stevens couldn't revive him.
莫尔在他脑袋上来了一枪
Merle put a bullet in his brain.
没举行葬礼
No funeral?
我们悄悄把他火葬了
We cremated him, quietly.
这些人经历的悲痛太多了
These people have been through so much,
谢天谢地  还好他只是个陌生人
I figured, thank God, at least no one knew him.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
把车开到院子上边去
Move the cars to the upper yard.
把它们头朝外
Point 'em facing out.
既不挡道
They'll be out of the way
需要的时候也能马上开走
but ready to go if we ever need to bail.
我们给那俩犯人
We'll give the prisoners
留能够吃一周的食物
a week's worth of supplies for the road.
他们怕是撑不了一周
Might not last a week.
那是他们的选择
It's their choice.
他们真有的选择吗
Did they really have one?
你手上想染上谁的血
Whose blood would you rather have on your hands--
玛姬的  格伦的  还是他们的
Maggie's, Glenn's, or theirs?
谁的也不想
Neither.
双汽缸的  是胜利牌的吗
Twin cylinder. Is that a Triumph?
别再看了
Don't even look at it.
想让它更拉风吗
Didn't want it bored out?
听起来发动机能调整一下
Sounds like it could use a tune-up.
我扳手活很厉害的
I'm pretty handy with a wrench.
水箱漏水了  我很懂摩托的
Heads are leakin'. I know my bikes!
伙计  你能别这样吗
Man, will you just stop?
有点种好吗
Have some balls.
就那么一说
Just sayin'.
慢慢来
Just take your time.
爸爸  别勉强自己
Daddy, don't push yourself.
我还能做什么
What else am I going to do?
我再也忍受不了
I can't stand looking up
继续看着那个床板了
at that bottom of that bunk anymore--
其实  我觉得自己挺稳的
You know, I think I'm pretty steady.
开了个好头
That's a good start.
要休息一下吗
Want to take a rest?
休息
Rest?
咱们不如出去转转
Let's go for a little stroll.
如果我们马上离开
If we leave soon,
黄昏前还能赶几小时路
we'll got a few hours on the road before dusk.
我们往哪里走
Where are we heading?
我想去海边
I'm thinking the coast.
一面可以用海水做掩护
We have the water completely on one side,
没准还能找条船
maybe we find a boat.
最好情况是找到个小岛
Best thing we can do is find an island.
如果海边也不安全呢
And if the coast isn't safe?
那就继续走
Keep moving.
就假设海边是安全的
Let's say the coast is safe.
然后我们干什么  慢慢变老
Then what do we do? Just grow old,
就我们两人独居荒岛吗
live off the sea by ourselves?
我宁愿冒着生命危险也不愿意留在这
I'd rather take my chances out there than stay here.
是因为你的直觉告诉你
Because your gut tells
这个地方和总督
you there's something off about this place--
都不太对劲吗
about the Governor?
我的直觉让我们活到现在
It's kept us alive this long.
这倒是事实
That's true.
这些食物够你们坚持一周
There's enough food in there to last you guys a week.
我们回来再放了你们
Cut you loose when we get back.
谢了  兄弟
Thank you, bro.
保重
Sit tight.
"谢了  兄弟"
"Thank you, bro"?
-要我把她干掉吗  -不
- Should I take her out? - No.
枪械库未必有弹药  我们要省着点
If that armory hadn't been picked clean, we could spare the ammo.
我现在就开始做围栏  越早越好
I'll start making runs. The sooner the better.
我们尽量在围栏里多扔点木头
We'll throw as much wood as we can in the dog run.
大火不会吸引更多行尸吗
Won't the fire attract more walkers?
也许我们应该埋了他们
Maybe we should bury them.
我们在栅栏后面
We're behind the fence.
最好能一次性把尸体都处理了
It's worth the one-time risk to get rid of the bodies for good.
我可不想在烂肉上种庄稼
I don't want to be planting crops in walker-rotted soil.
我在前边保护你
Got you here if you need it.
慢点下台阶
Just take your time on these steps.
你们把尸体都清出去了吗
You cleared all those bodies out?
这儿开始像个真正能居住的地方了
It's starting to look like a place we could really live in.
看好脚下的路
Hey, you watch your step.
我们可不想你摔倒
Last thing we need is you falling.
快看
Look at here.
他真是个硬汉
He is one tough son of a bitch.
还好吗  赫谢尔
All right, Hershel!
声音放低
Keep your cheers down.
我们就不能过一天好日子吗
Oh man, can't we just have one good day?
做得很好  爸爸
You're doing great, Daddy.
准备好赛跑了吗  赫谢尔
Ready to race, Hershel?
再给我一天
Give me another day.
我就跟你较量
I'll take you on.
行尸  小心
Walkers! Look out!
不
No!
快离开
Get out!
离开那里  快
Get out of there! Now!
洛莉
Lori!
走  快进去
Go! Come in here!
爸爸  你后面
Daddy, behind you!
快过来
Come on!
门锁  快点
The lock-- hurry up!
门锁
The lock!
给我钥匙
Keys!
那个门开着
That gate is open!
洛莉  这里
Lori! Here!
快点
Come on!
让开
Get out of my way!
快点  快点
Come on, come on!
兄弟  我们怎么办
Hey, bro, what about us?
不
No!
快跑
Hurry!
我在和达里尔
I circled where you can
待过的农场上做了标记
find that farm I was staying at with Daryl.
你是从九号公路
Ah, you were right off Route 9
和达洛尼加高速公路直切过来的
right before it becomes Dahlonega Highway.
你说农场离那里
And you're saying that the farmhouse
只有一天的路程吗
is only about a day's walk from there?
差不多
Give or take.
这是我们找索菲亚的地方
This is where we looked for Sophia.
在这儿也找过
Even made it up around here.
我们俩怎么从没勾搭过
How come we never hooked up?
你原来叫我妓女
You called me a whore...
还有臭婊子
and a Rod Muncher.
我嘴比较毒  不是吗
Got a way with words, don't I?
是的
Yeah.
你为什么把它给我
Why are you doing this?
如果我有家人  我也会担心他的安危
I'd want the same thing if it was my family out there.
你确定不想跟我一起去吗
Sure you don't wanna come with me?
你不想知道那伙人的下落吗
You ain't curious about the old gang?
你真的也被遗弃了啊
Oh yeah, you really was cut loose, weren't you?
他们肯定回来过找过我
I'm sure they came back.
我只是没有呆在原地等他们而已
I didn't stick around to find out.
我看你这是自我安慰
Ain't that a big ol' pig sack?
我们有共同点  金发美女
We got something in common, blondie.
都被同一伙人遗弃
We got left behind by the same people...
又被另一伙人救下
and saved by another.
你没想过离开这里吗
Have you ever thought about leaving this place?
我没理由离开
Never had a reason to.
总督是个好人吗
So the Governor is a good man?
这么说吧
Let me just put it this way--
他发现我时  我就是个废人
I wasn't in the best of shape when he found me.
他本可以弃我于不顾
He should have just kept on going.
是的  他是个好人
Yeah, he's a good man.
我们走  使劲拉
Let's go. Pull it!
-发生了什么  -大门开了
- What the hell happened?  - The gate was open!
洛丽呢  卡尔  其他人呢
Where's Lori, Carl-- everyone else?
玛姬带洛丽和卡尔进了C区  T仔被咬了
Maggie led Lori and Carl into C block. And T was bit!
其他人呢
Anyone else?
-不知道  -别乱跑
- I couldn't tell. - Stay put.
那些链子不可能是自己掉的
Those chains didn't break on their own.
有人用斧子或锁剪打开的
Someone took an ax or cutters to 'em.
-你认为是他们做的  -还会有谁
- You think they did it? - Who else?
那是什么
What's that?
不会吧
Oh-- you gotta be kidding me!
达里尔
Daryl!
弄停它
Kill it!
往后退
Back up!
怎么会这样
How the hell can this be happening?!
一定是备用发电机
Whoa-whoa-whoa! It has to be the backup generators.
发电机怎么会打开
Well, how do you turn those on?
有三个是连着柴油机的
There's three that's connected to a diesel tank, okay?
每个控制着监狱的一个部分
Each one controls a certain part of the prison.
监狱被侵占后它们都被关掉了
The hacks shut 'em all off when the prison was overrun.
电力够的话  主门会被打开吗
Can someone open up the main gates electronically with full power?
我只在这工作过几天
I only worked in there a few days.
我猜应该可以
I guess it might be possible.
-快跟我们走  -我们走
- Come with us! - Let's go!
有一组双扇门
There's a set of double doors
直通一个过道
that will lead to a corridor
可以让你重新回到牢房
that'll get you back to our cell block.
-你应该停下  -我要带你离开这儿
- You should stop. - I'm getting you there!
-停下  -怎么  坐在这儿等死吗
- Stop! - Why? Sit here and wait to die?
我会尽力帮你  你不会变成它们的
I'll do what I have to. You're not becoming one of those things.
我不能要求你那么做
I can't ask that.
我们要互相帮助  记得吗
It's the pact, remember?
这是上帝的旨意
This is God's plan.
他会关照我的  永远
He'll take care of me. Always has.
他会帮助我带你逃出这个隧道
He's gonna help me lead you out of these tunnels.
-你能跟得上吗  -我感觉不太对
- Can you keep up? - Something's not right.
-你被咬了吗  -不  不
- Are you bit? - No, no, no.
我好像快生了
I think the baby's coming.
妈妈
Mom?
不  没时间了  折回去
No, there's no time. Turn back.
进来这里
In here!
打得好啊
Pretty good.
我们应该去奥古斯塔(高尔夫俱乐部)
We should visit Augusta.
让女人们好好玩儿一下
Take only the women and let them play.
将是历史性转折
It'll be historic.
打破传统的枷锁
And break decades of tradition?
千真万确
Absolutely.
可能吧
I don't know.
但有些事情需要坚持
Some things are worth holding on to.
我想带着提姆和马丁内斯
You know, I was thinking of taking Tim and Martinez
在这周晚些时候外出行动
out on a scouting mission later on this week.
去干什么
For what?
那个金发女
Blondie.
她说我弟弟还活着
She said my brother was still alive.
八个月前
Eight months ago.
你或许有机会找到他们
You can track with the best of them,
但现在就像大海捞针
but it's like a needle in a haystack.
她告诉了我她们暂居的
She told me where I could find that farmhouse
农场位置
they were holed up in.
他可能在任何地方
He could be anywhere.
我了解我弟弟
I know my brother.
如果他还活着  我一定可以找到他
If he's out there, I'll be able to find him.
要是行动过程中出现伤亡呢
What if someone gets hurt during this search, huh?
还记得上次克罗利的遭遇吗
What almost happened to Crowley last time.
那我就独自去
Then I'll go on my own.
我了解你的感受  真的
I get what you're feeling, I really do,
但是我不能冒这个险  这里需要你
but I can't risk it. I need you here.
这个地方不能没有你
This whole place would fall apart without you.
那可是我弟弟
This is my brother.
这样吧
Tell you what, huh?
一旦你有了更可靠的消息
You get more concrete information,
我亲自陪你去
I'll go with you myself.
行不
All right?
洛莉
Lori!
卡尔
Carl!
刚刚又干掉了五个
We just took down five of them in there.
我在里面干掉了四个
There were four in here,
但没有洛莉和其它人的影子
but no sign of Lori or any of them.
他们可能被逼进监狱深处了
They must have been pushed back into the prison.
有人在耍我们
Somebody is playing games!
我们分头找其它人
We'll split up and look for the others.
不管谁先到达发电机房  关掉它们
Whoever gets to the generators first, shut them down!
走
Let's go!
这些警报是怎么回事
What are those alarms?
别担心
Don't worry about it.
警报招来行尸怎么办
What if it attracts them?
洛莉  赶紧躺下
Lori, let's lay you down.
不行  孩子就要出生了
No-- the baby's coming now.
我们得回到囚室找赫谢尔
We have to get back to our cell block and have Hershel help.
可能碰到行尸  我们不能冒险
We can't risk getting caught out there.
就在这里生小孩
You're gonna need to give birth to this baby here.
好吧
Great.
她怎么了  她好像呼吸困难
What is she doing? Can't she breathe?
她没事  过来  把你的裤子脱下来
She's fine. Come here-- let's get your pants off.
好吧
Okay.
好的
你要帮忙接生你的弟弟或是妹妹
You're gonna need to help deliver your brother or sister.
明白没有
You up for it?
我要检查一下  看你的宫口扩张没有
I'll do an exam. Let me see if you're dilated.
-好的  -你知道怎么做吗
- Okay. - Do you know how?
爸爸教过我  但这是我第一次自己接生
Dad taught me, but trust me, it's my first time.
-我看不出来  -我要用力了
- I can't tell. - I gotta push.
我要用力了
I gotta push.
老天
Somebody!
-我没事  我没事  -还好吗
- I'm okay, I'm okay. - Okay.
我没事
I'm okay.
你做得很好  继续
You're doing great, Lori. Just keep doing it.
跟着感觉走就是了  顺其自然
Your body knows what to do. Let it do all the work.
你做得很好
You're doing great.
洛莉  停下来  有点不对劲
Lori, stop, don't push, something is wrong.
就快到了
We're almost there.
快回去
Go back!
-不行  就快到了  -不要
- No. We're close. We're close! - No!
走  快走
Go! Go!
快走
走  当我死了
Go! I'm dead!
真不想你走
Sorry to see you leave.
看来并不是所有人都喜欢这里
This place isn't for everybody.
谢谢你为我们做的一切
Thank you... for everything.
打算去哪里
Where are you planning to go?
海边
The coast.
米琼恩说那里会比较安全
Michonne thinks it'll be safer.
你怎么看
What do you think?
好吧  她的警惕使你们活到了现在
Well, her vigilance has kept you both alive.
我有一段时间没喝烈酒了
Oh-- I haven't had hard liquor in a while.
我的酒量已经接近于零了
My tolerance is probably close to nil.
不喝也好
Lucky you.
莫尔说你告诉了他
Merle told me you provided information
他弟弟身处何处
about his brother's whereabouts.
那是我能做的  虽然不多
What I could. It wasn't much.
这给了他希望
Well, it's given him hope.
我觉得他找不到他弟弟
If you ask me, I don't think he'll find him.
-但是他会去找  -会去找
- But he's gotta look-- - Gotta look.
你呢
What about you?
觉得能找到自己要找的东西吗
Think you'll find what you're looking for?
什么意思
I'm sorry?
你还有家人活着吗
You still got family out there?
我失去了所有亲人
I lost my family.
父母  妹妹
My parents, my sister.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我失去了妻子  是车祸
Lost my wife-- car accident.
行尸潮爆发十八个月前
18 months before all this.
只剩下我女儿和我
Just my daughter and me.
愿明天更美好
To better days.
真好喝
This is good.
事实是  我都不知道自己在寻找什么
Truth is, I don't know what I'm looking for.
长久以来  都是为了活下来
For the longest time, it was all about survival.
其他的都不重要
Nothing else mattered.
以至于...
So much so...
我现在都不知道什么重要了
I don't know what matters now.
还车贷
Pay off the car,
每周工作五十个小时  结婚
work 50 hours a week, get married,
买房子  不久前很多人为这些事情而活
buy a house-- that was survival for many not long ago.
很多事情都变了
A lot's changed.
环境会变
The scenery has.
风景会变
The landscape.
但我们考虑问题的方式...
But the way we think...
我该走了
I better go.
谢谢美酒款待
But I appreciate the drink.
不客气
Sure.
莫尔会送你出去
Merle will see you out
他给你备好武器了
and he'll have your weapons waiting for you.
记住
Remember--
如果外面的生活很艰难
if it gets tough out there,
这里永远欢迎你
you're always welcome here.
你真好
That's very kind.
-谢谢你  总督  -叫我菲利普
- Thank you, Governor. - Philip.
我以为你不会告诉别人你的名字
I thought you never told anybody your name.
最近有人告诉我"凡事无绝对"  所以
Someone recently told me never to say never, so...
保重
Take care.
再见
Goodbye.
达里尔  守住门
Daryl, get the door!
怎么能把这关掉
How do you shut these down?!
过去帮他  这里我来
Go help him. I got it.
这里
Right here.
打死他  我们能夺回监狱
Shoot him! We can take back this prison.
你愣着干什么  射啊
What you waiting for? Do it!
这是我们的地盘  射他
It's our house. Shoot him!
(注意安全)
我们走
Let's go.
妈妈
Mom...?
妈妈  看着我  眼睛睁开
Mom, look at me, look at me. Keep your eyes open.
我们得把你送到赫谢尔那
We have to get you back to Dad.
我撑不住了
I'm not gonna make it.
洛莉  这么多血
Lori, with all this blood,
我想你的宫口还没完全打开
I don't even think you're fully dilated yet.
再用力也生不出来
No amount of pushing is gonna help.
我懂  我不会失去我的孩子
I know what it means, and I'm not losing my baby.
你得把我肚子切开
You've gotta cut me open.
-不  我做不到  -你别无选择
- No. I can't. - You don't have a choice.
-我去找人帮忙  -不
- I'll go for help. - No!
只有卡萝尔练习过剖腹产
Carol's the one that practiced that.
爸爸只教过我简单步骤  洛莉
Dad only taught me the steps, Lori. If I--
-拜托了  -我没麻醉药  也没设备
- Please. - I have no anesthetic, no equipment--
卡尔有把刀
Carl has a knife.
这样你就活不了了
You won't survive.
我的孩子必须活下来
My baby has to survive.
求你了
Please.
为了孩子  为了我们大家
My baby... for all of us.
求你了  玛姬
Please, Maggie! Please!
求你了
Please.
我以为我们说好了
I thought we had an agreement.
我们可以明天或后天再走
We can always leave tomorrow or the following day.
后天
The following day?
我们不该出去让自己身陷险境
We don't want to walk into trouble that we can't get out of.
-里面也未必安全  -米琼恩  就留一两天
- Tell me about it. - Michonne, it is just a day or two.
不用重复  我听到了
I heard you the first time.
看见以前剖腹产留下的疤了吗
You see my old C-section scar?
-我做不到  -你能做到
- I can't. - You can.
你必须做到
You have to.
卡尔
Carl?
宝贝不要害怕  好吗
Baby, I don't want you to be scared, okay?
这是我自愿的  这么做是对的
This is what I want. This is right.
替我照顾好你爸爸
Now you-- you take care of your daddy for me, all right?
还要照顾好你的弟弟或妹妹
And your little brother or sister, you take care--
你不必这么做
You don't have to do this.
你没事的
You're gonna be fine.
你能在这个世界生存  我知道你可以
You are gonna beat this world. I know you will.
你聪明  坚强
You are smart, and you are strong,
非常勇敢  我爱你
and you are so brave, and I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
宝贝  有时候必须做对的事情
You gotta do what's right, baby.
答应我  你会永远做对的事情
You promise me, you'll always do what's right.
在这个世界  做坏事很容易
It's so easy to do the wrong thing in this world.
所以别...
So don't--
如果感觉不对  就不要做  好吗
so if it feels wrong, don't do it, all right?
不要选择轻松的那条路
If it feels easy, don't do it.
别让这个世界污染你
Don't let the world spoil you.
你是个好孩子
You're so good.
我亲爱的孩子
You're my sweet boy.
你是我这辈子的骄傲  我爱你
You're the best thing I ever did. And I love you.
我爱你
I love you.
我最最亲爱的孩子  我爱你
You're my sweet, sweet boy. I love you.
好的
Okay-- okay, now.
好了
Okay.
玛姬  一切结束后你必须...
Maggie, when this is over, you're gonna have to--
-别那样说  -必须杀了我  不能让瑞克来
- Shh-- - You have to do it. It can't be Rick.
好了  好了
All right... all right.
没事的  没事的
It's all right. It's all right.
晚安  吾爱
Good night, love.
对不起  洛莉
I'm sorry, Lori.
你在做什么
What are you doing to her?
卡尔  帮我一把
Carl, give me your hands.
卡尔  拜托了
Carl, please.
你要保证这里干净  好吗
You should keep the site clean, okay?
切得太深  就会伤到婴儿
I cut too deep, I'm gonna cut the baby.
好了  快点
Okay, come on...
我看到了  我看到耳朵了
I see it. I see the ears.
我准备把孩子拉出来
I'm gonna pull it out.
我分不清这是胳膊还是腿
I can't tell if this is the arm or the leg.
好了  我把孩子拉出来
Okay, I'm gonna pull the baby out.
好的
Okay...
我们得走了
We have to go.
不能就这样走
We can't just leave her here.
她会变行尸的
She'll turn.
不行
No.
卡尔
Carl...
她是我妈妈
She's my mom.
我不会再把你当小孩
No more kid stuff.
人都有一死
People are gonna die.
我会死
I'm gonna die...
妈妈也是
Mom...
你永远无法心情平静的面对死亡
There's no way you can ever be ready for it.
赫谢尔
Hershel!
你们没找到他们吗
You didn't find them?
我们还以为他们回了这里
We thought maybe they came back.
-T仔呢  卡萝尔呢  -他们死了
- What about T? Carol? - They didn't make it.
T仔死了不代表卡萝尔也死了  我们再进去
That doesn't mean the others didn't. We're going back.
达里尔和格伦  你们跟我...
Daryl and Glenn, you come with--
她在哪里
Where-- where is she? Where is she?
别  瑞克  别去
No... Rick, no!
不
Oh, no. No!
No!